New York Public Welfare Association; Records apap126
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Administration, 1937-1994; 5; 0.6 cubic ft.
  The Administration series contains the records of the Board of Directors and the Association's budget reports. These dates are not inclusive. The Board of Directors records (1968-1994) contain letters of nomination, directions to the association for making important decisions and changes, meeting minutes, agendas, correspondence, expenditures, and actions taken on meeting resolutions. The budgets cover most every year, but are not inclusive as some years are missing. The budget records include charts and estimates, budget proposals for the coming year, and legal issues regarding the allocation of funds.
  - Advance Payments, 1980 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1968-1971 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1972 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1975 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1976/1977 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (5-Administration), Folder 7)
  - Budget, 1937-1945 (Box 2 (5-Administration), Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1960-1984 (Box 2 (5-Administration), Folder 2)
  - State Budget Analysis, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (5-Administration), Folder 3)
- Surveys, 1979-1986; 6; 0.4 cubic ft.
  Surveys were common during this period. These files contain many survey forms that were sent to all county commissioners to gain feedback on each county's local policy related to such subjects as child protection, cross matching, income maintenance, indigent burial, Medicaid, and state charge. These dates are not inclusive.
  - Child Protective Survey, 1980 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Cross Matching Survey, 1983 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Income Maintenance Survey, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Indigent Burial Survey, 1979-1985 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Indigent Burial Survey, 1986 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Medicaid Survey, 1981 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 6)
  - State Charge Survey, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (6-Surveys), Folder 7)
- Legal Issues, 1970-1995; 7; 0.4 cubic ft.
  This series is a collection of legal related folders such as the Governor's Council, Reports to the Governor, Social Security Law, Welfare Fraud Investigation, and Welfare Inspector General. These dates are not inclusive.
  - Governor's Council, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (7-Legal Issues), Folder 1)
  - Reports to the Governor, 1984 (Box 1 (7-Legal Issues), Folder 2)
  - Social Security Laws, 1970-1973 (Box 1 (7-Legal Issues), Folder 3)
  - Welfare Fraud Investigations Association, 1985-1995 (Box 1 (7-Legal Issues), Folder 4)
  - Welfare Inspector General, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (7-Legal Issues), Folder 5)
- Programs, 1961-1994; 8; 1.4 cubic ft.
  This series represents a plethora of public welfare programs. There is correspondence between the many departments of social services as well as reports on specific county programs. Programs include the Child Health Assurance Program (CHAP), the State Human Investment Program (SHIP), Home Energy Assistance Program (HEAP), Home Relief, Medicaid, Child Support, Food Stamps, Job Training, Employment and Homeless Issues, and a few county files. Of note is an important case study of public welfare that was conducted in Newburgh, New York in 1961; a folder is dedicated to this study.
  - Chemung County Managed Care, 1990-1992 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 1)
  - Child Health Assurance Program, 1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 2)
  - Child Support, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 3)
  - Child Support, 1981 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 4)
  - Child Support, 1982 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 5)
  - Child Support, 1983 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 6)
  - Employment, 1982 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 7)
  - Employment, 1983 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 8)
  - Employment, 1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 9)
  - Federal Register Grant, 1985 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 10)
  - Food Stamps, 1980-1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 11)
  - Home Energy Assistance Program, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 12)
  - Home Energy Assistance Program, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 13)
  - Home Relief, 1983 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 14)
  - Homeless Issues in New York City, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 15)
  - Nassau County Systems, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 16)
  - Homeless Issues in Westchester County, 1984 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 17)
  - Newburgh File, 1961 (Box 1 (8-Programs), Folder 18)
  - Medicaid, 1981-1984 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 1)
  - Medicaid, 1993-1994 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 2)
  - Mental Hygiene, 1977-1979 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 3)
  - Training, 1982-1983 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 4)
  - Training, 1984 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 5)
  - Training, 1984 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 6)
  - Training, 1985 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 7)
  - State Communities Aid Association Bulletin, 1985 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 8)
  - State Human Investment Program, 1982-1984 (Box 2 (8-Programs), Folder 9)